Connecticut Valley Tobacco Growers Association Records
© 2003 University of Connecticut
Connecticut Valley Tobacco Growers Association Records.
1920-1949
^Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center
Connecticut Valley Tobacco Growers Association.
271.5 linear feet.
The Connecticut Valley Tobacco Growers Association was a cooperative of tobacco growers that operated in Connecticut and Massachusetts during the early part of the twentieth century. The collection consists of the Association's records and printed materials which provide insight into the tobacco industry in Connecticut.
MSS19790005
History
The Connecticut Valley Tobacco Growers Association (CVTGA) was a cooperative of tobacco growers that operated in Connecticut and Massachusetts during the early part of the twentieth century.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of reports, accounts, ledgers, minutes, production records and publications. The materials spans the dates 1920-1949, but the bulk of the collection is dated between 1922 and 1926.
Organization
The collection is divided into three series:
Series I: Bound Volumes (undated, 1924-1926) is composed of 95 volumes containing production records, warehouse reports and sales analyses. Also included are selected corporate records such as expense accounts and stock ledgers.
Series II: Reports and Minutes (1922-1929) includes reports from the CVTGA similar in nature to the materials in Series I, except that they are not in bound volumes. The series also contains the minutes from the Board of Directors meetings (1922-1929).
Series III: Production Cards (1922-1926) contains individual Member Account Production Cards, which record member production. They are organized numerically by contract numbers assigned to each member. Eight boxes of index cards found at the beginning of the series cross reference the contract numbers with individual member information. The index cards are arranged alphabetically, as well as by location.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by format and chronologically therein.
Separated Material
Two trade journals, Tobacco (1920-1949) and Tobacco Leaf (1930-1944) have been removed for cataloging. Photocopies of The Connecticut Valley Tobacco Grower: Official Publication of the Connecticut Valley Tobacco Association (1923-1927, incomplete) has also been removed for cataloging.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut business records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Tobacco industry--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Publications.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; Ledgers.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division of the UConn Libraries (now Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center) in 1987 by E.A. Perregaux.
Detailed Description/Box and Folder Listing
- Series I: Bound Volumes, undated, 1922-1926
  - Assorting reports of tobacco delivered to warehouse: primed, roundtip, shade (2 volumes), 1924
  - Assorting reports of tobacco delivered to warehouse: broadleaf (7 volumes), 1924-1926
  - Assorting reports of tobacco delivered to warehouse: Havana seed (6 volumes), 1926
  - Summary analysis members' crops by pools: broadleaf (3 volumes), 1923-1924
  - Summary analysis members' crops by pools: Havana seed (3 vlumes), 1922-1924
  - Analysis members' crops by pools: broadleaf (2 volumes), 1922-1925
  - Analysis members' crops by pools: Havana seed (2 volumes), 1922-1925
  - Stock registers: broadleaf (6 volumes), 1922, 1924-1925
  - Stock registers: Havana seed (4 volumes), 1922-1925
  - Stock registers: shade, primed, roundtip, 1923
  - Preliminary grading of tobacco delivered to warehouse (4 volumes), 1923-1924
  - Analysis of sales by grade and pool (6 volumes), 1922-1926
  - Trial balance and general ledger, 1923
  - Trial balances (2 volumes), 1923-1924
  - Analysis of sales by customer and grade: Havana seed (2 volumes), 1923-1924
  - Analysis of sales by customer and grade (3 volumes), 1923-1925
  - Supplements of sales orders (4 volumes), 1922-1925
  - General ledger accounts, 1926
  - Stock ledger record, 1926
  - Analysis of Association storage warehouse expense, undated
  - General Accounts Department: expenses, undated
  - Analysis of members' crops by pool, undated
  - Analysis of members' numbers by pools (2 volumes), 1923
  - Analysis of sales by grade and warehouse (2 volumes), 1924
  - Stock ledger controls (3 volumes), 1922-1923
  - Reweight reports (5 volumes), 1922-1926
  - Accounting Department reports #2 - 4 (3 volumes), undated
- Series II: Reports and Minutes ,1922-1929
  - Reports and company records, 1922-1926 (Box 1-4)
  - Minutes of the Board of Directors and Executive Committee, 1922-1929 (Box 5)
  - Minutes of Board of Directors and Executive Committee, 1922 August 28 - 1923 June 19 (Box 6)
  - Minutes of Trustees in dissolution meetings,1929 (Box 6)
- Series III: Production Cards, 1922-1926
  - Member account production cards: index cards, 1922-1926 (Box 7-14)
  - Member account production cards: 1 - 299, 1922 (Box 15)
  - Member account production cards: 300 - 599, 1922 (Box 16)
  - Member account production cards: 600 - 899, 1922 (Box 17)
  - Member account production cards: 900 -1299, 1922 (Box 18)
  - Member account production cards: 1300 - 1699, 1922 (Box 19)
  - Member account production cards: 1700 - 2099, 1922 (Box 20)
  - Member account production cards: 2100 - 2499, 1922 (Box 21)
  - Member account production cards: 2500 - 2899, 1922 (Box 22)
  - Member account production cards: 2900 - 3299, 1922 (Box 23)
  - Member account production cards: 3301 - 3437, 1922-1923 (Box 24)
  - Member account production cards: 1 - 149, 1922-1923 (Box 24)
  - Member account production cards: 150 - 449, 1923 (Box 25)
  - Member account production cards: 450 - 799, 1923 (Box 26)
  - Member account production cards: 800 - 1149, 1923 (Box 27)
  - Member account production cards: 1150 - 1549, 1923 (Box 28)
  - Member account production cards: 1550 - 1949, 1923 (Box 29)
  - Member account production cards: 1950 - 2299, 1923 (Box 30)
  - Member account production cards: 2300 - 2699, 1923 (Box 31)
  - Member account production cards: 2700 - 3099, 1923 (Box 32)
  - Member account production cards: 3100 - 3499, 1923 (Box 33)
  - Member account production cards: 3500 - 3699, 1923-1924 (Box 34)
  - Member account production cards: 1 - 199, 1923-1924 (Box 34)
  - Member account production cards: 200 - 499, 1924 (Box 35)
  - Member account production cards: 500 - 799, 1924 (Box 36)
  - Member account production cards: 800 - 1099, 1924 (Box 37)
  - Member account production cards: 1100 - 1449, 1924 (Box 38)
  - Member account production cards: 1450 - 1799, 1924 (Box 39)
  - Member account production cards: 1800 - 2149, 1924 (Box 40)
  - Member account production cards: 2150 - 2499, 1924 (Box 41)
  - Member account production cards: 2500 - 2849, 1924 (Box 42)
  - Member account production cards: 2850 - 3199, 1924 (Box 43)
  - Member account production cards: 3200 - 3549, 1924 (Box 44)
  - Member account production cards: 3550 - 3899, 1924 (Box 45)
  - Member account production cards: 3900 - 4109, 1924-1925 (Box 46)
  - Member account production cards: 1 - 149, 1924-1925 (Box 46)
  - Member account production cards: 150 - 549, 1925 (Box 47)
  - Member account production cards: 550 - 999, 1925 (Box 48)
  - Member account production cards: 1000 - 1399, 1925 (Box 49)
  - Member account production cards: 1400 - 1799, 1925 (Box 50)
  - Member account production cards: 1800 - 2199, 1925 (Box 51)
  - Member account production cards: 2200 - 2649, 1925 (Box 52)
  - Member account production cards: 2650 - 3149, 1925 (Box 53)
  - Member account production cards: 3150 - 3649, 1925 (Box 54)
  - Member account production cards: 3650 - 4049, 1925 (Box 55)
  - Member account production cards: 4050 - 4125, 1925-1926 (Box 56)
  - Member account production cards: 1 - 449, 1925-1926 (Box 56)
  - Member account production cards: 450 - 1049, 1926 (Box 57)
  - Member account production cards: 1050 - 1549, 1926 (Box 58)
  - Member account production cards: 1550 - 2049, 1926 (Box 59)
  - Member account production cards: 2050 - 2599, 1926 (Box 60)
  - Member account production cards: 2601 - 3199, 1926 (Box 61)
  - Member account production cards: 3200 - 3999, 1926 (Box 62)
  - Member account production cards: 4000 - 4130, 1926 (Box 63)
  - Member account production cards: miscellaneous cards, all years: 1 - 399 (Box 63)
  - Member account production cards: miscellaneous cards, all years, 400 - 1399 (Box 64)
  - Member account production cards: miscellaneous cards, all years, 1400 - 1998 (Box 65)